( rock music on TV )
( phone rings )
Hey , babe , what 's up ?
( Katie ) What is that ?
- ( Micah ) Hello , baby . - Hi .
Is that what I think it is ?
( Micah ) I don 't know what you think it is , but it 's pretty sweet .
I think it 's a giant-ass camera .
What happened to the little hand-held ? Easy to move around . Versatile .
( Micah ) Are you going to park the car or stand there looking at me ?
This is big and impressive
and has a really bright light on it .
- ( Micah ) Kiss the camera . - I 'm not kissing the camera .
How much did this cost you ?
I 'll kiss you , not the camera .
- Turn that thing ... - Hmm ?
- ( Katie ) What are you doing ? - Yeah , see ?
( Katie ) Uh-huh . So you think this will work ?
( Micah ) I think we 're going to have a very interesting time
capturing whatever paranormal phenomena Is occurring or is not occurring .
Seriously , what did you throw down for that ?
( Micah ) Well , about half as much as I made today .
( Katie ) Good thing you 're cute . Dinner ?
- ( Micah ) Just keep going up the stairs . - Oh , my God .
- ( Micah ) Alright , I 'll make dinner . - Good .
( Micah ) We 're just gonna film whatever happens to us
and then when any weird shit goes on ,
we will be in a perfect position to capture it for posterity .
( Katie ) So we can always look back and remember fondly .
( Micah ) Hopefully , once we get it on camera ,
we can figure out what 's going on .
Once we know what 's going on , we can react appropriately .
And ...
( Katie ) Take it from there .
Take care of it , whatever it is .
If it 's one of those neighbours , one of those kids who is obsessed with you
and is trying to peep in through a window at night ,
that will take care of them .
Unless that kid has been following me around since I was eight years old ,
I don 't think that 's going to be the thing .
- That 's pretty creepy . - You 're telling me .
I realise that you 're , er ...
Are you OK ?
How you doing ? OK ?
Are you talking to the ...
Are you happy ? Do you have enough batteries ?
You 're supposed to be in love with me , not the machine .
We are going to be sleeping with this camera .
- We 're gonna what ? - Put it in the bedroom .
- All night ? - Uh-huh .
( Katie ) You 're cute .
- Yeah . - ( Katie laughs )
( Katie ) That was shy . You just looked away .
( Katie whispers )
Any time .
( Micah ) Test , audio test .
- This is the last test , right ? - Yeah . Can you just talk , please ?
Hello , Micah .
You 're the best boyfriend in the whole world ,
except for your strange fascination with electronics .
- ( Micah ) Katie , say something . - What do you want me to say ?
( Micah ) Something really quiet .
- ( whispers ) What do you want me to say ? - Whisper .
I am whispering . Can you hear me ?
( Micah ) Whisper .
- ( louder ) I am whispering . - You 're not whispering .
- ( whispers ) I 'm whispering now . - That 's a whisper , caught on camera .
Alright , sweet , this microphone is worth the cash .
- Alright , we 're operational , babe . - Whoo .
( Micah ) Sweet .
Do you know of any tricks to , er , make this stuff happen ?
I don 't want to make him , it , whatever ...
I don 't want it to happen at all , so ...
I don 't want to force it to happen .
You know , if it catches something , great . But I 'm not gonna like ...
( Micah ) I 'm just saying ,
cos having it on camera would be cool for a lot of reasons .
We could , you know ... It would substantiate your claims .
- You believe me , right ? - Yeah , course .
Hey .
( faint tapping )
What is that ?
Let 's investigate .
( Micah , whispering ) We 're hearing a weird sound .
( faint tapping )
( Katie ) Can you hear it ?
( tapping gets louder )
( Katie ) Is it the fridge ?
- ( Micah ) It 's the ice maker . - ( Katie sighs )
- ( Micah ) Damn it . - ( Katie sighs )
( Micah ) We weren 't coming out just to sleep here .
I 'd just like to take this moment
to illustrate the beauty of this fine instrument .
I meant her . This is just my guitar .
( laughs ) You 're sweet .
- What is this ? - I just like your feet . They 're sexy .
I need to repaint my toenails .
- ( Micah ) You look cute . - Shouldn 't film my feet .
( Micah ) Sex-type thing , can I get a little striptease ?
Please ? Just a half a one ? Just bra and panties .
- No . - ( Micah ) Alright .
I 'll do anything you want .
Bullshit .
( laughs )
( Micah ) Yeah , the Venus . Go back in your Venus pose .
( Katie ) Where are we going to put it ? The bathroom or the hallway ?
It should point down the hallway . That 's where we heard its footsteps .
( Micah ) It 's kind of dark .
- You can 't see me here ? - ( Katie ) Not at all .
( Micah ) What if I turn this one on ?
( Katie ) Yeah , that 's good .
( Micah ) That 's cool ? Think we need more light ?
( Katie ) No , I think you 're fine . Come check it out .
What happened with putting the camera up here ?
- You know , we should get ... - It 's got to get old , right ?
Be careful . You 're about to run into the shower .
We could get extra curricular with this . I know I 've mentioned it before .
- We could , but no . - OK .
Nice try , though .
I want you to know I 'm crying inside .
I 'm putting this thing back .
OK , I 'm gonna hook up the FireWire .
Going off .
( alarm beeps )
Working ? It is or isn 't ?
( Micah ) Yeah , I think it 's good .
( Micah yawns ) God !
Why don 't you put those slippers up ?
( Katie ) It 's looking at me .
( low rumbling )
( creaking )
( footsteps on stairs )
( keys jangle )
( silence )
( Micah ) This is what Katie looks like in the morning .
She 's so pretty .
( Katie ) What do you want for breakfast ?
( Micah ) Whatever . What the hell ...
( Katie ) Whatever isn 't an answer . How about scrambled eggs ?
- ( Micah ) Sounds pretty good . - ( Katie ) Yeah ? Good .
- ( Katie ) Hey , babe . - ( Micah ) What ?
( Katie ) Did you drop my keys on the floor ?
( Micah ) Hold on .
( Katie ) My keys are in the middle of the floor .
I just ... Look where I found my keys .
- ( Micah ) Where did you leave them ? - I left them on the counter .
( Micah ) Are you sure ?
( Katie ) Yes . I always leave them in the same spot , next to your wallet .
( Micah ) Obviously this is incontrovertible evidence
that evil forces came from beyond the grave to move your keys .
Make your breakfast .
( Katie ) That would be a 3.0 on the splash scale .
- What are you doing up there anyway ? - ( Katie ) I 'm filming you .
- Yeah ? - ( Katie ) Yeah .
( mimics gunfire )
( Katie ) Very , very mature .
- I think that 's my ... - I got a big one .
( Katie ) | I think that 's my favourite quality in you . Your maturity .
Big day . It 's the day of the psychic .
He 's coming , he should be here within the hour .
We 're going to find Micah and see how he 's feeling .
My guess ? Very excited .
Alright , tell me how excited you are to meet our psychic
who will be here within the hour .
- The doctor will be here , huh ? - Uh-huh .
I 'm just , like , so excited . I can 't contain myself .
( Katie ) Can 't contain yourself ? Let it all out . Don 't be shy .
I 've got something
quite appropriate for your psychic , I think .
- ( Katie ) What ? - I stumbled upon it .
( Katie ) Ooh , show me .
I 'll play this when he gets here , make him feel at home .
( eerie piano music )
( Katie ) You are totally not taking this seriously , are you ?
Don 't you want to make him feel at home and welcome in his own environment ?
( Katie ) This is not going to make him feel at home .
This is going to make him leave . We 're not gonna insult ... You , not me .
Don 't you smile like you 're so happy with yourself .
- How about less music ? - ( turns music off )
That was good .
Is this psychic going to give me some stock tips while he 's here ?
- Haven 't bet on the horses in a while . - ( Katie ) Maybe if you 're good .
Maybe he 's got an opinion on the 100-to-one shot .
( Katie ) I 'm done with you .
( Micah ) So , you 'd think a psychic would be on time .
You know , like he could foretell if the traffic was going to be bad .
- You 're clever . - ( doorbell rings )
( Micah ) Let me get my music .
Don 't you even think about turning that on .
- Hi . Dr Fredrichs ? - Katie ? Hi .
- Yes , hello . - Nice to meet you .
- Come on in , this is Micah . - Hi , Micah .
I 'm sorry for the camera .
( Micah ) Can you see ahead , that kind of thing ?
Like know when the traffic Is going to be bad .
Usually it depends on the day of the week or the time of the day .
Like all of us .
I never hesitate when somebody says come to San Diego .
Always ready to do that .
Well , I 'm certainly glad you made the trip . I really appreciate it .
I 'd like to spend time getting to know you ,
getting more information than what you shared over the telephone .
Getting to know both of you .
What 's your life like ? What 's your relationship like ?
- ( Micah ) It 's good . - It 's good . Well , that 's one good step .
Straight to the point .
- How long have you been together ? - Three years .
( Micah ) We 're engaged to be engaged , after she graduates .
- And your jobs ? Both of your jobs ? - I 'm a student .
I 'm an English major , looking to be a teacher soon .
I don 't know where yet . Micah is a day trader .
- How about your health ? - Erm , we 're in good health .
- No medications involved ? - No .
More often than not , things like you 've shared with me can be explained away
by simple things like squeaky houses or rattling pipes
or some normal things going on .
It just has people more freaked because they are highly stressed .
So this , let 's call it a haunting ,
has happened to you before moving into this house ?
Yes . It started when I was eight .
I , erm , you know , I was living with my family , of course .
I shared a room with my younger sister , Christi . She was five .
At that time we both experienced ... whatever it was .
I would feel the breathing wake me up and I would wake her up .
I would see the ...
I guess you 'd call it , like , just a mass ,
like , a shadowy , just , figure at the foot of my bed .
It was always at the foot of my bed , never her bed , but she did see it .
- ( Fredrichs ) She saw it also ? - Absolutely .
- We were both absolutely terrified . - ( Fredrichs ) OK .
Couldn 't even move , you know .
It was just ... It was horrifying .
You would just pray , " Please , let it go away . "
And then eventually it would .
This happened for a while in our first house .
And then , we ... There was a fire .
We managed ... Everyone got out , no one was hurt , thank goodness .
But , erm , we lost everything , SO we ... SO we moved .
( Fredrichs ) Was it determined what caused the fire ?
No . I 'm not saying it had to do with the haunting stuff .
I 'm not saying that at all . I don 't know what it was .
Did the fire department do any investigation of the causes of the fire ?
I don 't know if there was a criminal investigation ,
but they really tried to figure out what was the cause and they couldn 't .
It wasn 't electrical or anything simple like that .
So , from the time you were eight years old until now ,
have you experienced this periodically over the ensuing years ?
Yes . From 13 on , it 's happened periodically .
Over the past few weeks , things have started happening again .
When you tell me it 's moved from where you were living when you were eight ,
again when you were living some place else when you were 13 and now here ,
it seems that that 's what we 're dealing with .
Something that 's basically connected to you .
These lights have been flickering . These ones on the ceiling .
We 've had water from the faucets turn on and off inexplicably .
Not turn on and off , but we 'll come down and it will be on .
We 've heard banging on the walls , scratching sounds ,
you know , like dragging down the wall kind of scratches .
Most of the activity is in here , isn 't it ?
( Katie ) Yes . The vast majority of it .
Er , I 've heard whispering .
Sometimes I can 't understand it , sometimes it 's saying my name .
- So it specifically calls your name ? - It has before .
- You 've heard this , too ? - ( Micah ) I 've heard weird noises .
I haven 't heard anyone say Katie 's name except me .
It might have been me in my sleep .
I can tell the difference between you saying Katie from over there in the bed
and something right here whispering distinctly in my ear .
( Micah ) Yeah , so , look . I 've got a FireWire going in to my laptop .
We can record all night . You want to take this ?
Got the tripod , wide-angle lens to get the whole room .
EVP recorder . Just to catch any sounds .
So you 'll go to bed , have the light on and have the camera going ?
Do you do this all the time ?
( Katie ) We 've just recently started with the camera .
Extra bathroom right there .
Guest bedrooms . Lights flickering in here .
( Micah ) Is there something we can do
to make this stuff happen , to get it on tape ?
I don 't want to mess with that . I didn 't even want to get the camera .
These hauntings feed off of negative energy .
If there is something negative going on here ,
it will help spur on the haunting . This entity may feed off of that .
( Micah ) Shouldn 't let your mother come over any more . She 's really mean .
( Katie ) Stop joking .
My area of expertise Is dealing with ghosts .
That 's what I 've built my career around ,
helping people get in touch with people who have died ,
communicating with ghosts .
The spirits of dead human beings . A demon is something different .
That 's an entity that relates to something that is non-human .
There 's a lot of debate and a lot of discussion about what that could be ,
but it 's not a person , OK ?
Dealing with demons is not my area . I 'm very uncomfortable with it .
I 'll tell you frankly , I sense there is something going on in this house .
You cannot run from this . It will follow you .
It may lay dormant for years .
Something may trigger it to become more active .
It will , over time , reach out to communicate with you .
I 'll give you the name of Dr Johann Averies .
He 's a colleague of mine , a demonologist .
He specialises in this sort of thing . He 's in Los Angeles .
( Micah ) What about ... Check this out .
What if we get this Ouija board and we find out what it wants
and give it what it wants ? And then , gone .
Because what it probably wants is Katie .
And if you do pick up a board and try to play games with it ,
the entity will sense that you 're trying to communicate with it .
That 's opening the door , inviting it in .
- Do you understand me ? - ( Micah ) Yeah , I 'm with you .
I hope so . You 're gonna be fine . OK ?
( Katie ) Glad to hear you say that .
Thank you so much for coming .
I will definitely give Dr Averies a call .
- Have a very safe trip back . - I will . Bye-bye , both of you .
( Micah ) Later . What a fruit .
Do you think you could try not to be completely rude to him ?
I feel like it was good information . I feel like I 'm not nuts .
I feel like at least we 're doing something .
- I 'm gonna call that guy tomorrow . - What guy ?
- Dr Johann Averies . - ( Micah snorts )
- That demon guy ? - Don 't laugh .
Seriously , don 't call the guy . That 's insane .
- He said to call him tomorrow . - Don 't call the guy .
Promise me you 're not going to call that guy . Please .
I 'll put up with one dude .
I 'm not putting up with a legion of Jesus freaks .
- If it gets worse , I 'm gonna call him . - Alright .
You sound way better when you 're brushing your teeth .
How about a little extra-curricular activity ?
Not with this camera on us , no .
Turning the camera off for ten minutes .
- Ten minutes , huh ? - That 's all I need . ( laughs )
- Let 's go to bed . Turn it off . - Alright .
- I 'll set up in the bed . - Turn it off .
( Micah ) Katie is in the bathroom .
- Turn it off . - Hi , Katie .
( Katie ) I 'm trying to pee . Turn it off .
Dr Johann . I am Dr Johann .
- ( Katie ) I 'm about to pee . Go away . - I 'm a demonologist .
( Katie ) Gotta cover my pee . Can 't hear you .
I am here to save you from the demons .
- Come to bed . - ( Micah ) Oh , I will .
I 'm going to turn this off . Playtime ?
( Katie laughs )
- ( Katie ) Excuse me . - ( Micah ) What ?
- Camera 's not off . - It 's off . That 's the standby light .
That is not the standby light , that 's the record light . Don 't lie to me .
( Micah ) Alright .
I think that probably was illegal in Kentucky and another 12 states .
This girl is a wild animal .
( Katie ) When are you getting up in the morning ?
( Micah ) I don 't know . Six or so .
( Katie ) Did you set your alarm ?
( low rumbling )
( floorboard creaks )
( door handle rattles )
( door creaks )
( quiet indistinct noise )
( rumbling stops )
( alarm )
- You OK ? - Hm-hmm .
( Micah ) I was looking at the footage from last night .
Check it out . This is about 2 : 10 in the morning .
The doors ... You got it ?
The doors and windows all over the house are closed , I just checked .
The flowers are not moving .
- Something else is . - ( Katie gasps )
- The door is freaking moving by itself . - ( Katie ) Oh , my God .
( Micah ) It 's not over . Check it out . It moves again .
- ( Katie ) Oh , Micah , that is ... - That 's impossible .
( Micah ) I told you this was a good idea .
Wow .
( Micah ) You think you can get that ghost back ?
Think I can do what ?
( Micah ) Get the ghost back , get us some more interesting ...
I 'm not interested in that , I just want him to go away .
( Katie ) Oh , my God ! Micah ! Oh , my God .
( Katie ) What are you doing ? Come here right now .
- ( Micah ) What ? - It 's right there . Get it .
Get rid of it . Please .
( Micah ) You screamed like that for a spider ?
- ( Katie ) Oh , God . - Jesus .
( Katie ) Did you go get the camera first ?
( Micah ) I thought it was a ghost or something real scary .
( Katie ) I 'm nearly losing my mind and you grab the camera .
( Micah ) Hey , little friend , what 's your name ?
( Katie ) Can I turn the camera off ? OK , I need to not be around you .
- ( Micah ) Alright . - Straight outside . OK .
( Micah ) It 's going .
( Micah ) Hey , you out here ?
Hey , tell me what the point of this was .
This part of your master plan , just move the door ?
Or are you just doing random shit ?
Well , basically , it could be two things .
It could be a ghost or it could be a demon .
( Katie ) Dr Fredrichs said it wasn 't a ghost .
I 'm going by the evidence .
I 'm doing my research and I 'm going to find out what it is .
( Katie ) Whatever it is that 's following me , it doesn 't feel ...
Er , it doesn 't feel human .
It feels like it 's ... It feels like a monster .
Like it wants to hurt me .
- That sounds actually like a demon . - That 's what he said .
- Ghosts are spirits of human beings . - It 's definitely not human .
( Micah ) Then maybe you 're right , which is bad , because demons suck .
Basically they are these malevolent , evil spirits
that only exist to cause pain
and commit evil for their own amusement . It 's pretty creepy .
They stalk people for years , like decades .
Sometimes they 're really intelligent in the way they do things to freak you out .
This could be like a really rare phenomenon . It 's cool we got it on tape .
( Katie ) I 'm surprisingly not as excited as you ,
considering I 'm the one that 's being terrified .
It 's all good . We 'll take care of it .
I understand this stuff is new to you , and exciting in some ways .
So I get your whole filming thing .
But ... it isn 't new to me .
And I think this thing could be very dangerous .
So I just want you to know that if things progress or get worse in any way ,
I don 't want to mess with the camera . I don 't want to make it mad .
( Micah ) I understand .
Just remember that you didn 't exactly warn me about this kind of stuff
- before we moved in together . - I know .
( Micah ) So I think I have a little bit of a say in what we do .
I get that , but what was I supposed to say on our first date ?
" Hey , there 's a demon . "
( Micah ) No , but maybe on our 15th date or 30th date
or when we decided to live together , that might have been a good thing .
Do you agree with that ? OK .
( sets alarm )
( Micah ) Alright , windows are locked , doors are locked , alarm is on .
Anything gets in here , we 're gonna know about it .
( Katie ) I don 't think it cares about alarms and locked doors .
It can go wherever it wants , it can do whatever it wants .
( Micah ) How do you know ?
( Katie ) Whatever 's happening , it 's already here .
( Micah ) Alright .
( low rumbling )
( unintelligible , quiet voice )
( Katie gasps )
( Micah ) What is it ?
What 's the matter ?
( Katie ) I just ... I just had a nightmare .
Oh , my God !
I 'm sorry . Did I scare you ?
( Micah ) It 's alright , don 't worry about it .
- ( Katie ) Oh , my God . - You OK ?
- ( Katie ) Yeah . - You sure ?
( Katie ) My head .
( loud bang )
( Katie ) Did you hear that ?
- I 'm going down . - No , no , no , no , Micah .
Micah , don 't leave me here .
- Don 't leave me in here . - Take this .
( Micah ) Where do you think that came from ?
- ( Katie ) Micah ! - Anyone down here ?
- ( Micah ) That 's all you got ? - Oh , Micah , stop .
Please don 't do that .
Baby , come on .
( Micah ) You OK , baby ?
- I 'm OK . - You sure ?
I 'm still creeped out .
- ( Micah ) Hey , girls . - If you can just show me ...
( Micah ) Hello . Excuse me ?
I know it 's bead time , but I have something I want to show you guys .
Can 't it wait ? We 're having very intense girl time right now
and we cannot be interrupted by Micah and his camera .
- ( Micah ) Thank you . - I need a break from the filming .
( Micah ) What the fuck ? I want show you something .
Hey , you be sweet .
This is the tape from the digital audio recorder I set up in the bedroom .
This is the tape from about ten seconds before we woke up .
( unintelligible voice on tape )
- ( Katie ) What the hell was that ? - I listened to it 50 times .
It 's not anything , it 's not a language I recognise .
It 's not a dog . It 's not noise from the street .
It 's not any kind of electrical interference that I recognise .
- ( Katie ) Oh , God . - What I figure it is ...
- ( Katie ) That thing is in the bedroom . - ( woman ) Breathing on you .
This thing wants to communicate .
So I figure I 'm going to go out and get a Ouija board .
( woman ) No .
( Katie ) I don 't want to know what it has to say . I want it to leave us alone .
Trust me , bad idea .
( Katie ) He specifically said don 't do anything to antagonise or ...
Sorry I told you about it .
( woman ) If you use a Ouija board and invite it , it 's not gonna go away .
- Just let me do my thing . - ( woman ) It 's a bad idea .
( Katie ) The camera is your thing .
You do a Ouija board , there 's no more , nothing .
Promise me , Micah . Promise me , please .
Fine , I promise you I won 't buy a Ouija board .
( Katie ) Hey , Micah , smile .
( Katie laughs )
( Micah ) We haven 't had anything interesting happen in a while .
- ( Katie ) Micah ? - You scared ?
( Katie groans )
( Micah ) What you got ?
Put the camera away , we 're going to bed .
- Come on . - Go back to sleep .
- ( Katie ) Don 't antagonise ... - What you got ?
- Calling you out . - ( Katie ) Hey , that 's enough .
Micah . Come on .
( Micah ) Your demon 's worthless . You 're worthless ! You 're nothing .
( Katie ) Put the camera away .
( floorboard creaks / thud )
( Micah ) What 's up ?
( Katie ) I just thought I heard something .
( Micah ) What did you hear ?
( Katie ) Just a thud .
- ( Micah ) A thud ? Where ? - Maybe downstairs .
( eerie howl / loud crash )
- ( Katie sobs ) - Fuck !
( Katie ) Oh , my God .
Oh , my God .
Wait , wait , wait .
Micah . Wait , wait , wait .
Wait ! Please . Where 'd you go ?
( Micah ) I 'm right here , I 'm over here , babe . I 'm over here .
Over here .
( Katie ) Oh , my God .
( Katie ) Oh , God .
- ( Micah ) You OK , babe ? - Yeah .
( Katie sighs )
( Micah ) Looks like it 's gone now , whatever it was .
That 's video proof of that noise , though .
( Katie sighs )
( Micah ) Shh !
( faint scraping )
( Micah ) Do you hear that ?
Hold on .
( Katie ) Shh .
( faint noises downstairs )
You hear that ?
Yeah , I do . I don 't know what that is .
( Micah ) This is really good stuff , Katie . I 'm telling you , this is ...
I hope that guy , it , whatever , shows us a little more action .
- This is grade-A shit . - We shouldn 't be messing with this .
This is why it scares me , because you don 't take it seriously .
I take it seriously , I think it 's pretty ...
You have a camera in my face in the bathroom .
You look beautiful in the morning .
Maybe we shouldn 't have the camera .
( Micah ) Er , hello ? This is really golden shit . Come on .
Not an option at this point with all that cool stuff going on .
- ( Katie ) Cool ? - ( Micah ) Alright , disturbing .
- Are you not scared ? - ( Micah ) It 's a little bizarre .
But we have it documented . It 's going to be fine , OK ?
It 's kind of like it was coming from a wall or ceiling or something .
- ( Katie ) Or the floor . - Floor ? You think ?
( Katie ) Whatever it was ... Oh , God !
Like someone dropped something really big and heavy .
( Micah ) Like what ? Like someone picked the couch up or something ?
( Katie ) That kind of stuff didn 't happen to me before the camera .
- ( Micah ) Before what ? - Before the camera .
- It 's getting worse . - That has nothing to do with it .
It wasn 't that bad , it was a little loud .
It was my inner child being scared .
I 'm fine , thanks . Alright ?
( Micah ) EVP Experiment Number One . Is there anyone here ?
Where did you come from ?
You have something to say ? In English this time ?
Would you be happier talking with a Ouija board ?
( low rumbling )
What is your quest ? What is your favourite colour ?
( Micah on tape ) Where did you come from ?
You have something to say ? In English this time ?
( Micah ) It 's got nothing to say , huh ?
Would you be happier talking with a Ouija board ?
- ( grunting ) - Whoa . Hell .
- Is that you grunting ? - ( grunting )
( grunting )
What is it , like , one for yes , two for no ?
Yeah ? Crikes .
Yeah , let 's watch a movie , I don 't want to go to sleep yet .
- ( Micah ) Why not ? - Because I 'm scared .
( Micah ) Yeah ?
- Come on , put the camera off . - ( Micah ) Alright , OK .
( low rumbling )
( Micah ) Katie ?
Katie ?
You down here ? Babe ?
Fuck .
( insects chirrup )
Katie ?
Babe .
Katie , what are you doing out here ?
Katie ?
- Hey . - What ?
( Micah ) It 's freezing out here . What are you doing with no clothes on ?
- I 'm fine . - Come on .
No , I don 't want to go in .
Just leave me alone .
- ( Micah ) Are you OK , baby ? - Fine .
- ( Micah ) Come on . - No .
( Micah ) You just want to sit out here on the swing in the middle of the night
while it 's freezing ?
Yes . Go away .
( Micah ) I 'll stay out here with you . I 'll get some blankets , OK ?
Jesus Christ . What the fuck is going on ?
Ridiculous .
Got to get her out of the cold .
( loud bang )
What the fuck is that ?
Hey . Who 's there ?
Katie , come inside .
What the fuck is going on ? Come out .
Fuck .
( Katie ) What are you doing ?
( Micah ) What am I doing ? What the fuck are you doing ?
I heard noises up here .
I came in to get a blanket because you were on the swing for some reason .
- There 's all this stomping . - Come back to bed .
( Micah ) The TV is on .
Jesus .
I don 't know what the fuck is going on .
- ( Katie ) Cold . - I 'm going crazy .
( Micah ) So you don 't remember any of this ?
( Katie ) Erm , no . I mean ...
( Micah ) You don 't remember getting out of bed ?
You don 't remember standing there like a total weirdo ?
( Katie ) Hey !
( Micah ) I 'm sane , but ...
( Katie ) Oh , my God .
( Micah ) Were you sleepwalking ? What was going through your mind ?
( Katie ) I don 't know . I wasn 't ...
Oh , my gosh .
( Micah ) Yeah . So , what do you remember from this ?
I don 't remember anything .
I remember standing in the doorway and you pointing a camera at me .
You were all freaked out . I don 't remember standing here .
( Micah ) You went downstairs , sat in the swing . I went to get you a blanket .
Fast-forward it to where I go downstairs .
I 'm freaking leaving the room .
( Micah ) You went outside and sat on the swing .
And I went inside to bring you a blanket because you refused to leave
in this catatonic weird state you were in .
Wait , did I talk to you ?
( Micah ) I wouldn 't call it talking .
But I come upstairs and there 's footsteps and the TV is on .
So maybe this kind of thing has been happening for a long time
and you just never knew about it .
I don 't remember anything . I know that I had nightmares all night , and that ...
What ?
( Katie ) I didn 't want to talk about it .
Just , they were gruesome . Let 's leave it at that .
- It 's just trying to scare us . - It 's working . I 'm scared .
Just got to stay strong .
Not let it get to you and not let it get to us .
Bringing in somebody else , some exorcist or whatever ,
a lot of times it just gets worse . You don 't want it to get worse .
( Katie ) No , I don 't .
Yeah , alright , you little fucker .
Got something to say ?
Now 's your chance .
Katie . Where are you ?
( Katie ) I 'll tell you in a second .
( Katie 's footsteps )
( Katie ) I 'm so ready to get out of this house
and go out with my boyfriend .
We got , like , ten minutes .
( Katie ) What the hell are you doing , Micah ?
Come on and help me .
( Katie ) What are you doing ?
I 'm going to talk to it . I told you I was ...
( Katie ) You promised me you weren 't going to ...
Don 't look at me like that .
You promised not to mess with that stuff .
No . I promised not to buy a Ouija board .
( Katie ) Fuck you ! You knew what I meant .
I borrowed it .
( Katie ) How dare you ? You knew what I meant .
I said don 't mess with that stuff . It scares me .
And you buy the best Ouija board I 've ever seen
and put it in our living room .
- Explain that to me . - I borrowed it .
( Katie ) I don 't care . Throw it away .
We 'll leave right now .
There 's no more camera , no more nothing .
- I don 't want to hear it . - Katie , Katie .
( Katie ) Don 't " Katie " me . I 'm leaving .
You 're coming with me or you 're not .
( Micah ) Whoa . Chill , babe .
( Katie ) I don 't want to hear it .
( door slams )
( low rumbling )
( heavy footsteps )
( quick footsteps )
( door opens )
( Katie ) Take your shoes off and go to bed .
What did you do , Micah ? Look at me .
What did you do ?
( Micah ) I didn 't do shit , babe . Look . Whoa .
( Katie ) I cannot fucking believe you , Micah .
( door slams )
I am finished . No more fucking camera .
Nothing . I 'll take care of this .
If you 're not gonna do it then I will .
( Katie stomps up stairs )
( Micah ) Looks like someone drew something on it .
I don 't know .
- Hey , Katie . - ( Katie ) What ?
( Micah ) Can you come down here and help me figure this out , please ?
( Katie ) Sorry ?
( Micah ) I think this thing left a message on the Ouija board .
( heavy footsteps )
I don 't give a fuck what that thing says on the Ouija board .
( Micah ) Babe .
( door slams )
( Micah ) Katie . Look .
Katie . Hello ?
Micah , get the fuck out !
( Micah ) Whoa . Whoa !
- I don 't want to look at that . - Chill ! This is not the time for this .
Get out .
Get out !
( door slams )
I think she 's pissed . That 's not good .
( Micah ) Hey , Katie . Katie ?
Hello ? Look , I know you 're pissed , but ...
Do we have any lemon ?
( Micah ) What do I have to do ? Just tell me what I have to do .
You have to turn off the fucking camera .
( Micah ) Fuck . Forget the camera , OK ?
( Katie ) Hm-hmm .
I swear to abide by Katie 's rules and regulations
of camera use
and other things . Whatever .
It that good enough for you ?
( Katie ) I think it needs to be a little more sincere .
I swear to abide by Katie 's rules and regulations
of camera use
and to not offend this entity or whatever it is
in any way , shape or form ,
so help me God .
( Katie ) And I promise not to betray Katie 's trust .
I promise not to betray Katie 's trust .
- Is there anything else ? - ( Katie ) That 'll be it .
Good . Fuck .
( Micah ) Do I at least get a kiss for that ?
Please ?
( Katie ) Good night .
OK .
( Micah ) Katie . Do you want to know
what happened with the Ouija board ?
I saw the tape , you know .
( Katie ) I just want to forget about it , OK ?
Let 's go to sleep .
( Micah ) I 've found something that 's pretty cool
and I 'd like you to help me figure it out .
So , sit down .
Or stand up .
I caught on camera everything that happened after we left .
- The cursor was moving by itself . - OK .
I 'm trying to figure out what it said .
I couldn 't figure out exactly what it said . There 's a lot of possibilities .
Do you know anyone named Edina or Diane ?
Could be Nadine without two Ns . No .
- No . - Well , I 'll work on it .
It could be this thing is just fucking with us and it doesn 't mean anything .
It could be so many possibilities . I could be wrong . I don 't know .
I don 't really care what it means .
You 're done playing with it , I want it out of the house .
- ( Katie ) Every week something happens . - ( woman ) It 's crazy .
- I can 't ... I 'm at my w ... - ( Micah ) What are you talking about ?
Just everything .
- Come stay with me . - It 's not the house . It 's me .
Wherever I go , it goes .
So do I go to your house and mess things up for you ?
- ( Micah ) I got a plan , don 't worry . - Micah , what 's your plan ?
- ( Micah ) I got a plan . - What are you going to do ?
( Micah ) Don 't worry about it , OK ?
- ( Micah ) So ? - OK , here 's the compromise .
You can have your powder . You can do your little experiment .
If it doesn 't work and doesn 't help us ,
I 'm calling the demonologist and getting this taken care of .
- ( Micah ) Deal . - Can you look at me , not the camera ?
( Micah ) No . Deal . Alright , sorry . OK . Yeah ?
- Yeah . - Deal .
( Katie ) Alright .
- ( Micah ) Is that thing on ? - ( Katie ) Yes .
Exactly what is this gonna prove ?
( Micah ) Well , if anything walks through here ,
it 's gonna leave a pretty good footprint .
( Katie ) OK . I think we 've established something is happening .
Alright . Tomorrow I 'm making the call .
You can have your powder , you can clean it up tomorrow .
Take a deep breath , pop a pill . It 's fine .
- ( Katie ) Excuse me ? - Figure out what we 're dealing with .
- ( Katie ) Micah . - Then we can go crazy .
- ( Katie ) Pop a pill , my ass . - Does that look good to you ?
( Katie ) Looks like our floor is covered with powder .
- ( Micah ) I 'll clean it up . - ( Katie ) Alright .
( Micah ) That 's a thing of beauty .
- ( Micah ) Babe . - Yeah .
( Micah ) I 've been doing my research .
I 'm taking care of this . Nobody comes in my house , fucks with my girlfriend ,
gets away with it .
You want to call the demon guy ?
- Yes , exactly ! - Call an exorcist ?
I want to take care of this .
I 'm taking care of it .
This is my house , you 're my girlfriend .
I 'm going to fucking solve the problem .
- OK ? - ( laughs ) OK .
Just have a little faith .
- ( Katie ) This is it . - What 's it ?
( Katie ) The powder is the last .
The last thing .
Tomorrow I 'm going to make the phone call .
Too cute to be talking .
( low rumbling )
( heavy footsteps )
( Katie ) Did you hear that ?
- ( Micah ) Oh , shit ! - ( Katie ) Oh , my God !
Oh , my God .
( Micah ) You know what ?
There 's footsteps in but there 's no footsteps out .
( Katie ) Oh , God .
( Katie ) Don 't leave me here .
( Micah ) Turn on the light , baby .
( Katie ) Let 's just go downstairs .
It 's still here . Let 's go .
- ( Micah ) Oh , no . I can 't run . Or you . - ( Katie exhales )
( Micah ) What ?
The prints stop over here .
( Katie ) Micah , this could be a trap . Please , let 's go .
Oh , my God !
Did you do that ?
You didn 't , Micah ? Tell me you opened that .
( Micah ) Course not .
What the hell is that ?
( Katie breathes deeply )
( Katie ) You 're not going up there . You 're not going up there .
( Micah ) I am not going in there . Just gonna ...
- Just gonna look . - ( Katie ) No , you 're not .
( Micah ) I got to go check it out . I 'm getting the ladder .
( Micah ) OK . It 's all set up .
( Katie ) Micah , I really don 't want you to go up there . Please .
( Micah ) I 'm not going in there . I 'm just going to look .
( Katie ) You have no idea what 's up there . You have no idea .
( Micah ) I know .
Give me the camera .
- Yeah . - Be careful .
If something goes wrong , I 'm gonna throw you the camera and jump out .
( Katie ) Do you see anything ?
Micah , I don 't want to be down here by myself .
( Micah ) I 'll be right back .
What the fuck is that ?
There 's something over there stuck in the ...
( Katie ) Micah , come back down . Come on .
Micah , please , come on .
( Micah ) What the hell is that ?
- Hold on to me . Here . - ( Katie ) What ?
- ( Micah ) Just take the camera . - OK , come on .
I 'll hold the ladder . Come down .
( Micah ) Something 's up there . I got to look .
( Katie ) Micah ! Oh , God .
Micah , please be careful .
Are you OK ?
Micah , answer me .
Micah . Micah !
( Micah ) I 'm fine .
( Katie ) Oh , thank God .
( Micah ) Fuck .
Found this up there .
( Katie ) No . No , no , no , no .
Let me see that .
- ( Micah ) What are you talking about ? - This is our old house .
What in the hell is this doing in the attic ?
( Micah ) It 's all burned out .
( Katie ) There 's no way . There is no way you found that in our attic .
There is no way that that even exists .
I haven 't seen that picture in 15 years .
That makes no sense .
That makes no sense at all .
( Micah ) You OK , babe ?
- Turn the light off , please . - ( Micah ) Sorry .
Where was it when you found it ?
( Micah ) It was over our bed .
- I 'm going to clean up this stuff . - OK .
I have no idea if I 'm gonna get to class today .
God , I am so tired .
Why are you filming me ? I 'm just making coffee .
I 'm actually sick of this .
I think we could both use a little more sleep .
I think I could use a new life . I 'm so tired of this .
- Take a look at this . - ( Katie ) Take a look at what ?
I lightened up the footage from last night .
Can you see the footsteps ?
( Katie ) Oh , my God .
So ?
- What ? - ( Katie ) What are you gonna do ?
Hmm ?
I don 't know yet .
( Katie ) Well , I do . We 're calling Dr Averies .
You 've had your camerawork . You 've had your powder on the floor .
It 's just gotten worse . We should have done this two weeks ago .
We 're calling him today .
( Micah ) Hey , hey , hey . Let 's talk about this first .
I 'm in control . I 'm making progress .
No , you haven 't been having any progress and you 're not in control .
It is in control .
If you think you 're in control then you 're an idiot .
Not a single thing you 've done has helped .
I don 't mean to burst your bubble ,
but the camera hasn 't helped and the footprints haven 't helped .
Do you think it would have left footprints if it didn 't want to ?
It did it because it wanted to . It wanted you to find my photo .
It can be anywhere . It hears what we 're saying .
- ( Micah ) How the fuck do you know ? - You are absolutely powerless .
( Micah ) That 's not true at all . You know it .
Get over it .
( sighs ) Er , well , I called Dr Averies and he 's gone .
I didn 't know what else to do so I called Dr Fredrichs back .
I know you don 't love him , but I did .
He 's coming back tomorrow . That 's as soon as he could get here .
If we make it till then , hold off ...
- ( Micah ) We 'll make it till then . - I 'm just saying .
- ( Micah ) Make it till then . God ! - We could hold out , we 'll be OK .
Maybe tomorrow , he 'll help us .
( Micah ) Fucking people . Ridiculous .
( footsteps / low rumbling )
( footsteps coming up the stairs )
( fast footsteps )
( Micah ) Fuck !
( Katie ) What are you doing ? What are you doing ?
- What did you hear ? - ( Micah ) There 's something out there .
( loud banging )
- ( Micah ) Fuck ! - ( Katie ) Oh , God !
( Micah ) Goddamn it !
( Katie ) Come here , don 't go . Please , baby , please .
( door rattles )
( Micah ) I 'm going out there .
( Katie ) Don 't , don 't . Please , please .
Don 't open it .
( Katie breathes heavily )
Micah , come on . Come on .
Right now . Come on . Micah .
( Micah ) Who 's there ?
- ( Katie ) Baby , come on . - ( Micah ) Want to fuck with us ?
( Katie ) Micah , don 't . Come on . Let 's go .
( Micah ) Show yourself .
( Katie ) Come on , Micah , let 's go .
- ( Katie ) We 've got to get out . - ( Micah ) Got a problem ?
- ( Katie ) Stop ! - ( Micah ) Alright , I 'm sorry .
- ( door slams ) - ( Micah ) Whoa !
( Katie pants )
( Katie ) Micah .
( door rattles )
- ( three heavy knocks on door ) - ( Katie sobs )
( Katie ) Please . Don 't open it .
( Katie shrieks )
( Micah ) Oh , it 's scaring us .
Hey , hey , hey .
Shh .
- It 's not gonna make a difference . - I 'm not going in that bedroom .
- Micah , please . - ( Micah ) Baby , look . It comes back .
( Katie ) No . Downstairs , let 's just ... Please .
( Micah ) Baby , shh .
It 's not going to make a difference . Come on .
( Katie ) I don 't want to be in here . Downstairs .
Please , please , please , please , please , please .
- Please . - Alright .
( Micah ) What the hell is in here ?
I don 't know if down here Is gonna be much better .
( creaking )
( Katie ) Micah .
( creaking / footsteps )
( Katie ) I don 't want to be here .
( Micah ) Maybe we should go upstairs again . Come here .
( Micah ) OK ?
Babe ?
OK ?
You know , you gotta get some sleep once in a while .
I 'm just scared .
I couldn 't be in that room any more .
( Micah ) OK . I understand .
Can you believe this house , Micah ?
We can 't even be in our house .
- ( loud bang ) - What the fuck is that ?
( Micah ) I 'll check the mirrors .
( Katie ) Our picture .
- ( Micah ) What picture ? - ( Katie ) That one , look .
( Micah ) What the fuck ?
What the hell ?
How come my face is scratched and yours isn 't ?
( Katie ) Something 's here .
( Micah ) This is bullshit .
- ( Katie ) It 's here . - ( Micah ) What 's here ?
What ? What are you talking about ?
I don 't know . Feel it . I feel it breathing on me .
Micah ! Come on ! Come on ! Please !
( Micah ) Fuckin ' - A , man .
- ( Katie ) Babe . - ( Micah ) Jesus Christ .
( Katie ) Micah , come downstairs . Come on .
( Micah ) Has this shit happened in the daytime before ?
( Katie ) It 's getting worse .
( Micah ) Fuck .
- ( Micah ) Baby , stop pacing , please . - I 'm sorry .
- ( Micah ) It 's making me nervous . - Well , I 'm nervous .
( doorbell rings )
- Katie , hi . - Dr Fredrichs , hi . Come in , please .
- Thank you so much for coming back . - Not a problem .
We called Dr Averies but he 's gone .
- Yes , he 's out of the country . Wow . - We need your help .
- This is overpowering . - It 's getting worse .
It doesn 't like that I 'm here and I cannot help you .
I 've got to get out . This thing is very aggravated .
- ( Micah ) You can 't leave us alone here . - We need your help .
I 've got to tell you , I am not the person to help you in this situation .
This is not my area of expertise .
I think I 'm doing more harm being here than any good .
I really have got to leave .
Dr Averies will be back in a few days and he " ll take care of the problem .
( Micah ) What should we do ? Should we leave ?
Leaving won 't help at all .
I 'll see what I can do . I have to leave this room .
- ( Micah ) This is no joke . - I will help you .
- I can 't do this right now . - No , no , no , no .
( Micah ) Serious ?
( Micah ) Take care of this ourselves , OK ?
Katie ?
Fuck .
( sobs )
I 'm so fucking tired .
- I know you are . - Oh , God .
I don 't want it to be like this .
( low rumbling )
( knocking )
( low grunt )
( Katie gasps )
- Micah . Micah . - What 's the matter ?
I just ... I just felt him breathing .
Right there .
He was right there . I felt him breathing .
What are you doing ?
Where are you going ? Come back .
I 'm not going anywhere . Chill .
There 's nothing there , babe .
I 'm telling you . I 'm telling you .
Please .
I can feel it . He 's still here .
- Something 's wrong . - Shh .
Take a deep breath , OK ?
I can feel it watching me .
Right now .
( Micah ) Fucking freaking me out , babe .
- We have to do something . - ( Micah ) What ?
I don 't know . We have to figure something out .
- We have to ... - ( Micah ) OK , OK .
We 'll figure something out . Do some research .
There 's got to be some other options .
( Micah ) This shit is creepy .
( Katie ) I knew something happened last night .
( Katie gasps )
( Katie ) We 've got to do something . I can feel something is wrong .
( Micah ) I was doing some research , trying to figure out our options .
I found this website .
This chick , Diane . One of the possibilities from the board .
She had all the same things happen to her in the ' 60s
- that 's happened to you . - What do you mean ?
( Micah ) Everything , like from eight years old , the house burning down ,
seeing shadows and whatever . God knows .
And she called an exorcist .
Is that her ? You 're telling me there 's some girl from the ' 60s
who had the exact same things happen to her ?
( Micah ) Down to a T. Maybe this thing is the same thing .
It 's just jumped to you instead . It 's his MO or whatever .
He 's trying to warn us with this Ouija board ,
trying to tell us to find this woman , so we know ...
So , what happened to her ? Is she OK ?
( Micah ) They tried to get rid of it
and sometimes it just pisses it off more .
Before the exorcist got there , she wasn 't like this .
She was just hearing voices and having bad dreams .
I 'm trying to find some kind of reason
this thing would pick you after haunting her .
I can 't find anything .
From what I 've read , these things are totally random .
- There 's no reason , like ... - How did she die ?
( Katie ) She 's pretty .
( Micah ) Now she is .
I think it 's trying to warn us not to fuck with it .
I don 't want to take a chance .
( Katie ) Oh , God .
( Micah ) There 's no way we 're doing this .
It 's gone away on its own before . It 's not worth the risk .
I 'm going to go lie down .
( Micah ) Katie , I 've got an idea about what we can do , some more stuff .
Would you please get away from me with that camera ? I 'm trying to study .
( Micah ) I want to talk to you about this thing .
Micah , please , will you give me five minutes ?
Go , please .
( Micah ) Hey , chill out .
I 'm trying to help this situation here . I have some ideas .
You and your stupid camera are the problem .
- ( Micah ) What the fuck ? - Just leave me alone .
Stop following me with the camera !
( Micah ) I 'm trying to solve the problem .
I didn 't bring that thing in the house . You did !
Thank you , Micah . Thank you so much .
( Micah ) Go hang out with your friend upstairs . I 'll be down here .
- ( Katie ) Shut up ! - ( Micah ) Oh , whatever .
( sobs hysterically )
( Micah ) Hey !
( Katie ) I 'm sorry .
( Micah ) You didn 't do anything wrong .
You didn 't do anything wrong . It 's not your fault .
Listen to me , it 's not your fault . You haven 't done anything wrong .
( low rumbling )
Micah . Micah !
Micah ! Micah ! Micah !
- Katie ! - ( Katie screams hysterically )
( loud banging )
( Micah yells )
( Micah ) No !
( Katie ) Micah ! Micah !
( Katie sobs )
( sobs hysterically )
I don 't care , I just want to go .
I just want to go . I can 't ... I can 't ... I can 't be here . I can 't ...
Let 's go , please , let 's go . Let 's just get in the car .
( Micah ) Yeah . Why are we leaving ?
I 'll get us a hotel , stay there tonight until we figure out what we 're doing .
We 're not staying here another night .
( Micah ) Let me get a shot of that thing it made on your back . OK ?
Is that OK ?
Oh . Jesus !
( Kate winces )
( Micah ) Sorry . It looks like something bit you .
( Katie ) I know .
Let 's go .
( Micah ) Hey . Are you ready to go ?
Car 's packed . Let 's go .
Hey , babe ?
Babe ? Hey .
Honey .
What the fuck ?
Babe . Let go of this thing .
Let go .
Jesus Christ .
Babe .
It 'll fucking kill us . Katie .
Katie . Katie . Wake up . Jesus .
Had it with this shit !
( yells )
Baby .
Come on , let 's go .
Let 's get you up . Come on . Hey .
Come on . Come on .
Let 's get to the couch . Come on .
Had it with this shit . Taking care of this right now !
Fuck this shit , I 'm done .
( Micah ) Katie .
- Ready to go ? Let 's get out of here . - Babe .
( Micah ) I packed the car . Let 's go .
I don 't want to go .
What are you talking about , you don 't want to go ?
Let 's get the fuck out of this house .
I don 't want to leave . Will you stay with me ?
( Micah ) What the fuck are you talking about ? We 're leaving .
I think it will be better if we stay .
Please . Just ... I don 't want to go . I don 't want to leave . Just trust me .
( Micah ) Whoa ! You wanna stay here ,
sleep in this bed and get dragged down the hall again ? I don 't think so .
We 'll be OK . It 's better if we stay .
( Micah ) Are you fucking crazy ? Alright .
I don 't know what the hell is going on , but this is insane .
Fuck ! Ah !
( low rumbling )
( voice echoes ) I think we 'll be OK now .
( knocking )
( Katie walks downstairs )
( rumbling stops )
( Katie shrieks )
Katie !
( Katie screams )
( Micah ) What 's the matter , honey ?
What ? Oh , my God !
( heavy thuds / Micah screams )
( silence )
( heavy footsteps )
( low rumbling )
( heavy footsteps continue )
( heavy footsteps )
( heavy thud )